

#### **MELL PICCO**

# www.mellpiccodesign.com

ph. (410) 952-5765 mellpiccodesign@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

User Research
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Testing
User Interface Design
Responsive Web Design
Front End Development
Identity & Branding
Print Design & Production
Environmental Design
Illustration

# TOOLS

**Design:** Adobe XD, MarvelApp, Balsamiq, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Acrobat

**Development:** HTML, CSS, WordPress, MySQL, PHP, JavaScript, Atom, MAMP, Eclipse, ZK

**Motion Graphics:** Animate, After Effects, Autodesk 3ds Max

**Sound:** BandLab, GarageBand, MOTU CueMix, Max MSP

## **MEMBERSHIPS**

UXPA DC AIGA Baltimore Monument Women's Creative Alliance AFCEA

# identity> print> web> user experience> design

#### **PROFILE**

I am a user-focused design professional with over fifteen years of experience collaborating with clients to express their unique visions. I believe data-driven research and usability testing are critical to creating the best design and experience for users.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Advanced User Experience (UX) Design Program** (06/2021-07/2022) CareerFoundry

User Experience Design (06/2021-02/2022)
User Interface Design Specialization (02/2022-04/2022)
Front End Development Specialization (04/2022-07/2022)

An intensive training program for UX Designers, specializing in research methodology, user flows, wireframes, prototyping, and User Interface best practices. During this program, I designed user-friendly responsive websites, analyzed user-flows and enhanced usability through testing.

## Bachelors of Fine Art in Graphic Design (2001-2005)

Maryland Institute College of Art

**Fine Art Courses** (June 2001)
Community College of Baltimore County

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PiccoTek Inc., Design Principal/Director of BD (2003-05; 2008 - Present)

- Designed company identity and continues to carry branding throughout stationery, website, employee portal, time card system, trade booth, signage, company briefs, perpetual calendar, and promotional materials.
- As Director of Business Development, builds business strategies and maintains customer relationships in the Department of Defense community.
- Develops proposals, creates eye-catching layouts and infographics.

#### Mell Picco Design, Owner/Designer (2008 - Present)

- Worked with clients in construction, music & entertainment, publishing, nonprofit, information technology and hospitality industries
- Services include: Website Design, Social Media Marketing, Identity & Branding, Environmental Graphic Design, Trade booths, Marketing Collateral,
   Packaging & Press Kits, Illustration, Book Design and Self Publishing.

#### **Design Collective, Inc.,** Junior Graphic Designer (2005-2008)

- Created branding and advertising projects for the Marketing Team including: Design of annual Holiday calendar, promotion announcements, trade booths, award announcements, award submissions, proposal covers, and invitations.
- Design of company's lobby environmental graphics including: entrance graphics, a reception sign and gallery wall.
- Managed graphics projects to meet needs of the Architecture, Planning, and Interiors Studios including: presentations and colorizing plans or renderings.
- Responsible for coordinating photo shoots of company's architectural projects as well as maintaining and updating the photography library, image server, project sheets and website.
- Streamlined workflow for Creative Team and mentored Design Intern.

#### Expert Consultants, Inc., Graphic Design Intern (Summer 2001)

• Aided in the design of an interactive website to showcase the capabilities and help files of this Information Technology company's new software program, FlexST.



EveryBody, Health Tracking App



InvestNest, Responsive Real Estate Site



PiccoTek, Inc. WordPress Website



Restaurant WordPress Website



Vocabulary Learning App Design



Protect Ellicott City Branding

# identity> print> web> user experience> design

#### RECOMMENDATIONS

"I have worked with Mell over the past several months as she has polished her user experience skills in the CareerFoundry program. Students come to the program with a range of skills. In Mell's case, she came with a strong work ethic, a good eye for design, and site design experience. These all have contributed to some thorough analysis, solid finished product, and a desire to learn and iterate. She'll be a great asset to any design team."

#### - Steve Arrington, CareerFoundry Mentor/ UX Designer

"Mell is an extremely talented energetic designer, illustrator and artist. I got the opportunity to work with her at Design Collective and as a fellow designer I was delighted at the flow of creativity we could generate between us. She thinks outside of the box and can add a wonderful sense of humor to her creations when appropriate. She can also create a very clean, sophisticated product. As a result, Mell is versatile and able to produce work that matches the client's vision. She is an exceptionally hard worker and pays close attention to detail. I know this first hand because we worked many overtime hours together and she did it with a smile and that great sense of humor. I highly recommend her!"

## -Amanda Denney, Graphic Designer

"Mell has worked on several digital graphics projects for the Chive Maryland charity community where maximizing audience reach through brand recognition, high visibility and familiarity was the goal. Her creativity, responsiveness and feed back are top notch. Mell has always been a pleasure to work with and we continue to enjoy leveraging her expert services for our community and our event sponsors."

#### -Michael Castro, Chive Maryland Administrator

"Mell created a unique invitation and thank you card set for my wedding, as well as eye-catching flyers for our non-profit's fund-raising events. She has also worked on many packaging, screen printing and marketing designs for my husband's business over the years. She is a talented artist who asks all the right questions to give her clients the end product they need. I would recommend her to anyone needing quality graphic design work."

# -Lindsay Koschoreck, Leader at Charm City CCFA Young Professionals

"I had the pleasure of working with Mell during her time with us here at Design Collective. As part of our marketing team, Mell was responsible for supporting our Interiors studio. We miss her very much."

-Lou Ghitman, Principal & Director of Interior Architecture at Design Collective, Inc.

"Mell Picco is truly a full-service designer. Her marketing efforts are comprehensive, creative and cutting edge!"

-Sally Costello, Business Development & Urban Redevelopment Professional

# www.mellpiccodesign.com